tripz.com 2006-06-15

# Tripz.com :: Privacy Policy

**Updated and revised as March 8, 2005**   
PLEASE READ. YOUR USE OF THIS SITE IS SUBJECT TO THE FOLLOWING PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT AND THE WEB SITE TERMS OF SERVICE.TRIPZ.COM™ (“TRIPZ.COM™”) publishes this Privacy Policy to inform you of our practices concerning the collection and use of information you provide us through interactions with this website (the “Site”). This policy is not applicable to information gathered by other methods or controlled by other agreements. Your use of this Site or any services available on this Site constitutes acceptance of this Privacy Policy and any other applicable terms. The Terms and Conditions of Use for this Site are hereby incorporated by reference. 

**How We Collect Information**   
We collect personal information in a variety of ways, including when you register with TRIPZ.COM™ on this Site, when you subscribe to TRIPZ.COM™ services through this Site, when you use TRIPZ.COM™ products or services via the Site, and when you enter Internet-based promotions or sweepstakes sponsored or administered by TRIPZ.COM™. 

**User Registration**   
If you register on our Site, we ask for and collect information such as your name, email address, birth date, gender, and zip code. For some products and services we may also ask for your address and information about you or your business’s assets or income. Once you register with our Site and sign in to our services, you are not anonymous to us. 

**hot dealz Newsletters**   
Users may elect to participate in a variety of TRIPZ.COM™ hot dealz newsletter (email services). We collect personal information in connection with the registration for and use of such services. 

**Contests** Users may elect to participate in promotions and/or promotional contests that we conduct from time to time on behalf of our clients. We collect personal information in connection with user registration for and participation in such promotions and contests.   

**IP Addresses** We automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, TRIPZ.COM™ cookie information, and the website page you request. We use this information to help diagnose problems with our servers, for system administration, and to examine our Site traffic in aggregate. The information may be collected and used to improve the content of our Web pages and to customize content and/or layout for each user.   

**Use of Information**   
If you elect to provide us personal information, we use it primarily to deliver the service you requested. We may use personal information in a variety of ways including the following: •  We may use personal information collected through the Site to send out targeted email promotions on behalf of our advertisers and industry partners.   
•  We may combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from business partners or other companies in order to better deliver products and services that may be of interest and benefit to you.   
•  We may use personal information to send notification of our or our partners’ products and services by such methods as email.   
•  If you provide financial information, we use that information to verify your credit and collect payments for your purchases, orders, subscriptions, etc.   
•  We may send product announcements or special edition newsletters to online registrants.   
•  We occasionally conduct subscriber and/or user surveys to better target our content to our audiences. The aggregated information collected is sometimes shared with our advertisers; however, this aggregate information does not include personally identifiable information.   
We have numerous products and services and therefore numerous email and promotion lists. In an effort to allow users to tailor their participation in TRIPZ.COM™ services and promotions, we provide users the ability to choose specific lists or products of interest and opt-out options are product and use/list specific. All email promotions sent from TRIPZ.COM™ provide an opt-out link at the bottom of the email pursuant to which users can opt-out of specific products and promotions. If you receive one of these emails and wish to unsubscribe please follow the instructions given in each email or contact privacy@tripz.com.   
From time to time we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our Privacy Policy. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our Site. 

**Sharing of Information Collected With Third Parties**   
In general, we do not rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or nonaffiliated companies except to provide products or services you have requested. We will, however, make your personal information available to others under the following circumstances: •  When we have your consent (you “opt-in”) to do so, in which case your information is subject to the privacy policy of the third party(ies).   
•  We may provide personal information about our users to trusted partners and vendors who work on behalf of or with TRIPZ.COM™ under confidentiality and similar agreements prohibiting such parties’ further use of the information. These companies may use your personal information to help us communicate with you about offers from us and our marketing partners. However, these companies do not have any independent right to use or share this information.   
•  Where we have a good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a judicial proceeding, a court order, or legal process served on us, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.   
•  Where we have a good faith belief that it is necessary in order to investigate (or assist in the investigation of), prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of TRIPZ.COM™ 's terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.   
•  If TRIPZ.COM™ is acquired by or merged with another company, we will transfer information about you to this other company in connection with the acquisition or merger. 

**Reviews and Ask the Experts**   
Users may post reviews on TRIPZ.COM™ based on their experience and knowledge of a particular travel destination, category, suppliers, etc. Participants should be aware that information disclosed in such reviews is made available to all users and thus becomes public information. We suggest that you exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information when posting reviews to the Site. 

**Disclaimers**   
We are not responsible for any breach of security or for any actions of any third parties that are inconsistent with this Privacy Policy and/or the terms and conditions under which such third parties are receiving information. TRIPZ.COM™ also links to a wide variety of other sites and contains advertisements of third parties. We are not responsible for their privacy policies or how they treat information about their users. 

**About Children's Privacy**   
This Site is not intended for use by children, and TRIPZ.COM™ does not knowingly collect information from children. You must be at least 18 years old to access or use this Site. 

**Update/Change Your Data**   
To update your email address or change your email preferences (including opting out from any specific products or promotions) please contact privacy@tripz.com. 

**Changes to this Privacy Policy** We reserve the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, change, update or modify this Privacy Policy, simply by posting such change, update or modification on the Site. Any such change, update or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the Site. Users will be informed of changes to this Privacy Policy via the “updated as of” link on the Site.   

**Third Parties on our Site**   
Our Site may contain advertisements, references and links to other web sites and organizations. We may also use third parties to display or serve content and advertising on the Site. These third parties may employ cookie and web bug technologies to measure advertising effectiveness. You should be aware that different rules may apply to the collection, use or disclosure of your information by third parties in connection with their advertisements, promotions and other web sites you encounter on the Internet. The use of such technology by these third parties is within their control and not ours, and even if we have a relationship with the third party, we do not control those sites or their policies and practices regarding your information and we encourage you to investigate and ask questions directly of them in this regard. We do not share any of the individual personal information you provide us with the websites to which TRIPZ.COM™ links, except as stated elsewhere within this Privacy Policy, although TRIPZ.COM™ may share aggregate data with such websites (such as how many people use our Site). TRIPZ.COM™ will use reasonable efforts to advise our users that they have exited an TRIPZ.COM™ operated website and are entering a third party controlled website. Customers/users should read and understand any privacy policy noted on all third party websites. 

**What Else Should I Know About My Privacy When Online?**   
Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example through email, discussion lists, or elsewhere - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.   
Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your personal information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online. 

**Your California Privacy Rights**   
Under a provision of California law, a California resident who has provided personal information to a business with whom he/she has established a business relationship for personal, family, or household purposes ("California customer") is entitled to request information about whether the business has disclosed personal information to any third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. Alternatively, the law provides that if the company has a privacy policy that gives either an opt-out or opt-in choice for use of your personal information by third parties for marketing purposes, the company may instead provide you with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options. 

This Site qualifies for the alternative option. As stated in our Privacy Policy, users of the Site may opt-out or opt-in to the use of your personal information by third parties. Therefore, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of the third parties that received your personal information during the preceding year for marketing purposes. To prevent disclosure of your personal information for use in direct marketing by a third party, do not opt-in to such use when you provide personal information on the Site. Please note that whenever you opt-in to receive future communications from a third party, your information will be subject to the third party's privacy policy. If you later decide that you do not want that third party to use your information, you will need to contact the third party directly, as we have no control over how third parties use information. You should always review the privacy policy of any party that collects your information to determine how that entity will handle your information. 

California customers may request further information about our compliance with this law by e-mailing privacy@tripz.com. You should put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the subject field of your email. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this email address. 

**Your Consent To This Policy**   
By using our Site, you consent to the collection and use of information by us as specified in this policy. Please also note that your use of the Site is governed by the Terms and Conditions of Use posted on this Site. If you do not agree to the terms of the Privacy Policy or the Terms and Conditions, please do not use the Site or its products and/or services. Please send any questions about this Privacy Policy to privacy@tripz.com. 

© 2005 Alliance Reservations Network TRIPZ.COM™ is a registered trademark of Alliance Reservations Network
